And if your brain is failing at integrating bad news about the future, you will constantly leave your rose-tinted spectacles on. So we wanted to know, could we change this? Could we alter people's optimism bias by interfering with the brain activity in these regions? And there's a way for us to do that. This is my collaborator Ryota Kanai. And what he's doing is he's passing a small magnetic pulse through the skull of the participant in our study into their inferior frontal gyrus. And by doing that, he's interfering with the activity of this brain region for about half an hour. After that everything goes back to normal, I assure you. (Laughter) So let's see what happens. First of all, I'm going to show you the average amount of bias that we see. So if I was to test all of you now, this is the amount that you would learn more from good news relative to bad news. Now we interfere with the region that we found to integrate negative information in this task, and the optimism bias grew even larger. We made people more biased in the way that they process information. Then we interfered with the brain region that we found to integrate good news in this task, and the optimism bias disappeared. We were quite amazed by these results because we were able to eliminate a deep-rooted bias in humans. And at this point we stopped and we asked ourselves, would we want to shatter the optimism illusion into tiny little bits? If we could do that, would we want to take people's optimism bias away? Well I've already told you about all of the benefits of the optimism bias, which probably makes you want to hold onto it for dear life. But there are, of course, pitfalls, and it would be really foolish of us to ignore them. Take for example this email I recieved from a firefighter here in California. He says, "Fatality investigations for firefighters often include 'We didn't think the fire was going to do that,' even when all of the available information was there to make safe decisions." This captain is going to use our findings on the optimism bias to try to explain to the firefighters why they think the way they do, to make them acutely aware of this very optimistic bias in humans. So unrealistic optimism can lead to risky behavior, to financial collapse, to faulty planning. The British government, for example, has acknowledged that the optimism bias can make individuals more likely to underestimate the costs and durations of projects. So they have adjusted the 2012 Olympic budget for the optimism bias. My friend who's getting married in a few weeks has done the same for his wedding budget. And by the way, when I asked him about his own likelihood of divorce, he said he was quite sure it was zero percent. So what we would really like to do, is we would like to protect ourselves from the dangers of optimism, but at the same time remain hopeful, benefiting from the many fruits of optimism. And I believe there's a way for us to do that. The key here really is knowledge. We're not born with an innate understanding of our biases. These have to be identified by scientific investigation. But the good news is that becoming aware of the optimism bias does not shatter the illusion. It's like visual illusions, in which understanding them does not make them go away. And this is good because it means we should be able to strike a balance, to come up with plans and rules to protect ourselves from unrealistic optimism, but at the same time remain hopeful. I think this cartoon portrays it nicely. Because if you're one of these pessimistic penguins up there who just does not believe they can fly, you certainly never will. Because to make any kind of progress, we need to be able to imagine a different reality, and then we need to believe that that reality is possible. But if you are an extreme optimistic penguin who just jumps down blindly hoping for the best, you might find yourself in a bit of a mess when you hit the ground. But if you're an optimistic penguin who believes they can fly, but then adjusts a parachute to your back just in case things don't work out exactly as you had planned, you will soar like an eagle, even if you're just a penguin. Thank you. (Applause)
Y si tu cerebro está fallando al integrar malas noticias sobre el futuro, llevarás puestas constantemente tus gafas de color de rosa. Queríamos saber, ¿podremos cambiar esto? ¿Podremos alterar el optimismo de la gente interfiriendo en la actividad cerebral de estas regiones? Hay una manera de hacerlo. Este es mi colaborador Ryota Kanai. Y lo que está haciendo es pasar un pequeño pulso magnético a través del cráneo del participante en el estudio hacia su circunvolución frontal inferior. Y haciendo esto, está interfiriendo en la actividad de esta región del cerebro durante aproximadamente media hora. Después de esto todo vuelve a la normalidad, se los aseguro. (Risas) Veamos qué sucede. Primero que nada, voy a mostrarles la cantidad media de predisposición que encontramos. Si fuera a examinarles a todos Uds. ahora, esta es la cantidad que aprenderían más de las buenas noticias comparado con las malas. Ahora interferimos con la región que averiguamos que integra información negativa, y la predisposición al optimismo se hace incluso mayor. Hacemos que la gente esté más predispuesta en el sentido en el que procesan la información. Entonces interferimos en la región cerebral que encontramos que integra buenas noticias, y la predisposición al optimismo desapareció. Estábamos asombrados con estos resultados porque fuimos capaces de eliminar una predisposición profundamente arraigada en los humanos. Y llegados a este punto, paramos y nos preguntamos, ¿querríamos destrozar en pedacitos la ilusión del optimismo? Si podemos hacerlo, ¿querríamos quitarle a la gente la predisposición al optimismo? Bien, ya les he hablado de todos los beneficios que tiene la predisposición al optimismo, la cual probablemente haga quieran aferrarse a ella desesperadamente. Pero por supuesto existen inconvenientes y sería realmente estúpido de nuestra parte, ignorarlos. Tomemos como ejemplo este e-mail que he recibido de un bombero aquí en California. Dice, "Investigaciones con bomberos sobre casos con víctimas mortales normalmente incluyen 'No pensamos que el fuego fuera a hacer eso' incluso cuando toda la información disponible estuviese allí para tomar decisiones seguras". Este capitán va a emplear nuestros hallazgos acerca de la predisposición al optimismo para intentar explicar a los bomberos por qué piensan de la manera en que lo hacen, con el fin de hacerles del todo conscientes sobre la predisposición al optimismo de la gente. Es que el optimismo no realista puede llevar a un comportamiento peligroso; al colapso financiero, a una planificación deficiente. El gobierno británico, por ejemplo, ha reconocido que la predisposición al optimismo puede hacer que los individuos sean más propensos a subestimar el coste y la duración de los proyectos. Así que han ajustado el presupuesto de las Olimpiadas del 2012 teniendo en cuenta la predisposición al optimismo. Mi amigo que se casa dentro de unas semanas ha hecho lo mismo con su presupuesto para la boda. Y por cierto, cuando le pregunté sobre de sus posibilidades de divorciarse, dijo que estaba seguro de que eran del 0%. Lo que quisiéramos hacer, es protegernos a nosotros mismos de los peligros del optimismo, pero al mismo tiempo mantener la esperanza, beneficiándonos de los muchos frutos del optimismo. Y creo que hay una manera de hacerlo. La clave aquí es el conocimiento. No nacemos con un entendimiento innato de nuestras predisposiciones. Deben ser identificadas a través de la investigación científica. Pero la buena noticia es que ser consciente de la predisposición al optimismo no destruye la ilusión. Es como las ilusiones visuales, en las que entenderlas no las hace desaparecer. Y esto es bueno porque significa que podríamos encontrar un equilibrio, cumplir los planes y las reglas para protegernos del optimismo no realista, pero al mismo tiempo permanecer esperanzados. Creo que este dibujo lo refleja bien. Ya que si eres uno de los pingüinos pesimistas de allá arriba que simplemente creen que no pueden volar, ciertamente nunca lo harás. Porque para hacer cualquier tipo de progreso, necesitamos ser capaces de imaginar una realidad diferente, y además necesitamos creer que esa realidad es posible. Pero si uno es un pingüino con un optimismo extremo que salta ciegamente al vacío esperando lo mejor, puede encontrar un pequeño desastre cuando llegue al suelo. Pero si uno es un pingüino optimista que cree que puede volar, pero que se pone un paracaídas en la espalda por si las cosas no van exactamente como las ha planeado, volará como un águila, incluso si uno es sólo un pingüino. Gracias. (Aplausos)